Kanade. I love you.
小奏，我喜歡你
Do you know there's a way to hold hands that can never be separated?
-危險啊… -你知道絕對不會鬆手的握法嗎？
I got a call from a girl.
有女生找我
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來
Kanade's dad was--
小奏的爸爸…
Don't say it!
別說了！
This might be the end…
我們之間的友誼…
of our friendship.
可能到此為止了
Why are you here?
為什麼你會在這裡？
-I missed you. -You don't know…
-我好想你 -你知不知道我們幾個
how hard it was for us to get over the death of Kaori.
要克服香織離世的事有多難？
I've never forgotten her. Not ever.
我從沒忘過她，一次也沒有
You'd better not see Masaki.
你不能跟真樹見面喔
You have Takashi now.
現在你身邊已經有貴志先生了
Don't you think… it's time we get married?
我們差不多該結婚了吧
This is a tough one.
對方出的招真是棘手啊
The former prosecutor has come out to squash us.
前檢察官要來擊敗檢方了
This is out of the blue.
怎麼這麼突然？
All I want is to know the truth.
我啊，只是想知道真相
What the hell is this?
這算什麼啊？
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
是你殺害了辻英介吧？
That's why I…
所以說…
Kaori was…
我將香織…
Kanade, wait!
小奏，等一下！
Wait a second.
別走啊
Sorry, I can't. Let's go, Kaji.
抱歉，加地，我們走吧
Are you sure?
這樣好嗎？
Since that day,
自從那天之後
Masaki's voice won't stop echoing in my ears.
真樹的聲音便一直縈繞在我耳邊
There can't be any doubt about what he said at that moment.
當時他確實是這樣說的
He said Eisuke Tsuji was killed.
“是你殺害了辻英介”
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
是你殺害了辻英介吧？
Is this your first time?
是初犯嗎？
Yes, it's my first time.
是的
Your…
你的…
Masaki's father, Koichiro Nogi, killed my father?
真樹的父親野木浩一郎 曾殺害我父親？
That's why I… Kaori was…
所以說…我將香織…
And what does that have to do
此事和香織的意外
with Kaori's accident?
又有何關聯？
ENVIRONMENTAL ENERGY CORRUPTION CASE
（環境能源貪汙案）
Hello. This is Nishimura.
你好，我是西村
It's been a while. I have a little favor to ask you.
好久不見，我有事情想拜託你
I want to see the documents for a case from the Tokyo District Office.
我能調閱東京地檢的案件資料嗎？
Yes. A case around 2004.
對，2004年左右的
TO KANADE NISHIMURA
（西村奏檢察官收）
FROM TOKYO DISTRICT OFFICE
（東京地方檢察廳）
My father was involved as a prosecutor
父親以前作為檢察官參與其中的
in the environmental energy corruption case.
環境能源貪汙案
When the trial was over,
就在公開審判之後
my father committed suicide
父親自殺了
right in front of me.
就死在我面前
My father was kind.
父親是如此溫柔
Kana Kana, come here.
奏奏，過來吧
When I was a child, he used to play with me often.
在我小時候，他經常陪我玩
Way to go!
就是那樣…
At the time, I didn't even know what sort of work he was doing.
我卻對父親的工作內容一無所知
What's your job, Daddy?
爸爸，你的工作是什麼？
Daddy's job is called a prosecutor.
爸爸的工作是檢察官
What's a prosecutor?
什麼是檢察官？
Hmm, it's hard to explain.
這個嘛，還真難解釋
There are people who do bad things, right?
有時候不是會有人做壞事嗎？
Uh-huh.
嗯
We catch those bad people, and judge if they really were bad.
爸爸就是要把那個人抓起來 判斷他是不是真的壞人
Then we try to make them turn into good people by--
然後為了幫助此人改邪歸正…
I don't understand.
聽不懂啦
Yeah, it's hard to understand, isn't it?
也對，很難懂吧？
For some reason, I remember that day very well.
不知為何，我還清楚記得那一天
The park at dusk, walking side by side with my father.
我們在黃昏的公園並肩走著
The warmth of my father's hand.
父親的大手很溫暖
My commitment to a sense of justice.
是貫徹正義吧
That might be it.
這是我的想法
You asked me about my job. Didn't you, Kanade?
奏奏不是問我在做什麼工作嗎？
Yeah.
對
Daddy's job is to be committed to what I believe is justice.
爸爸的工作啊，就是貫徹自身的正義
Or…
應該說…
maybe it's a job that tests you
這份工作會考驗我
if you can commit to a sense of justice or not.
是否能貫徹正義
My father changed when I was in the sixth grade.
父親在我小學六年級時出現了轉變
It was after we moved from Takamatsu to Tokyo.
那是我們從高松搬來東京之後的事
Is Dad not coming home again tonight?
爸爸今天也不會回來嗎？
He's on a business trip for a while so he won't be coming home.
是啊，他說暫時要去出差
His work required him to be away from home for days at a time.
他變得經常忙於工作 好幾天都無法回家
Welcome home.
你回來啦
Hello, Kanade.
小奏，我回來了
At home, he didn't talk much anymore.
回到家也變得不太會說話
I felt scared to talk to him sometimes.
我有時甚至會害怕跟他搭話
May 19th, 2003…
2003年5月…
Kanade.
小奏
Don't get in your father's way. Go to bed now.
別去打擾爸爸，快睡吧
On May 19th…
5月19日…
I found out that my father worked in the special investigation squad
我是透過電視新聞才知道
of Tokyo District Public Prosecutors Office.
原來父親隸屬於東京地檢特搜部
He was leading the search of an office of a sitting Diet member
處理在任國會議員貪汙案時
POLICE SEARCH THE OFFICE OF DIET MEMBER AZUMA
（特搜部搜索東議員住家）
My father, the prosecutor in charge,
父親以該案的主任檢察官身分
ordered the arrest of the Diet member.
逮捕了議員
But when the trial started, it became clear
然而開庭之後
that the prosecution had fabricated evidence in the case.
卻查出整起案件是檢方捏造的
My father, who was supposed to be catching bad people,
原本應該是逮捕壞人的父親
found himself considered to be the villain.
在不知不覺間卻成為了惡人
And then he…
然後父親…
Am I the only one summoned?
只有我要出面嗎？
The case is a fabrication by the prosecution.
案件是檢方所捏造的
It was a completely rash move by the police.
這次的逮捕 完全是出自警方的急功近利
It is outrageous.
太離譜了！
An indictment is impossible.
不可能被起訴
The attorney who exposed the fabrication by the prosecution
揭開檢方捏造案件一事
and caused my father to get arrested was
使父親被逮捕的律師是…
Koichiro Nogi.
野木浩一郎
UPSET WIN BY ATTORNEY OF JUSTICE
（逆轉勝的正義律師，野木浩一郎）
An indictment is impossible.
不可能被起訴
It is outrageous.
太離譜了！
Yes.
請進
Do you have a moment?
可以打擾一下嗎？
You seem to be researching something on your own recently.
你最近好像私下在調查些什麼
Well, I…
沒有…
Is it about Eisuke Tsuji, the former prosecutor?
是關於前特搜部的辻英介？
Did you know about my father?
你知道家父的事？
It was easy to figure out even with the change in your surname.
即便你改了姓氏 那點小事我很快就能查出來了
That's fine for now.
算了
You have a visitor.
有訪客找你
The "attorney of justice" is here.
正義律師大駕光臨了
What?
什麼？
Thank you for waiting.
讓你久等了
Be careful.
小心應對
You never know when you'll be caught flat-footed in this business.
在這世界，你不會知道自己 何時會出其不意地被算計
Try not to repeat the mistakes of your father.
千萬別重蹈覆轍，跟你父親一樣
Thank you for making time in your busy schedule.
抱歉在百忙之中打擾
Not at all.
不，你言重了
I wanted to apologize for the other day.
我想為前陣子的事道歉
At Yokohama District Court.
就是在橫濱地方法院的時候
Oh, it's all right.
請別介意
Was that day… the first time we met?
那時是我們第一次見面嗎？
Uh, not exactly.
那個，其實不是
I didn't meet you in person,
我沒有正式見過你
but I'm familiar with your face and name from that illegal drug case.
但在之前的違法藥物案 有得知你的名字與長相
Oh.
這樣啊
And…
另外…
once before that.
我以前還見過你一次
I was at university.
是在我讀大學的時候
When Ms. Kaori Oikawa had that accident,
及川香織小姐出意外後
I saw you at the police station in Nagano.
我曾在長野的警察局看過你
I see.
原來如此
I know Masaki caused so much trouble.
真樹給你添麻煩了
It's all right.
沒關係
The reason I came here is--
我今天來是為了…
Is it about my father, Eisuke Tsuji?
是為了談家父辻英介的事而來的嗎？
Um…
那個…
Oh, excuse me.
沒事，抱歉
I was surprised by your bluntness.
只是覺得你問得真直接
It's because I too
其實我也很想見你一面
wanted to meet you face-to-face and ask you some questions.
有些事我想當面請教
Ask me? About what?
你想問什麼呢？
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
是你殺害了辻英介吧？
About the case
20年前
which my father was involved in 20 years ago.
家父任職於特搜部時調查的
The environmental energy corruption case.
環境能源貪汙案
I see.
這樣啊
In that case,
在那起案件中
you were the attorney for the Diet member my father indicted for bribery.
你是以收賄罪起訴家父的 國會議員的律師
Yes, I was.
是啊，沒錯
This almost feels
現在這個樣子
like an interrogation.
總覺得像是在接受偵訊
The special investigation squad was abuzz over the arrest of a sitting Diet member.
特搜部逮捕在任國會議員 引起軒然大波
Well, I can imagine.
可想而知吧
But when the trial started,
然而當公開審判開始
every last bit of testimony up until that point was retracted.
之前的證詞全都被推翻
This was all done by a skilled attorney.
一切都是出自一位優秀律師之手
I don't know if I'm that skilled.
我倒是不清楚自己優不優秀
The Diet member was acquitted,
該國會議員被判無罪
and my father was accused of deciding to indict even though he knew
家父明知那封決定 賄賂事件成立的祕書信件
that the key evidence email had been fabricated.
是假造的，仍堅決起訴
And he was dishonorably discharged.
因此遭到懲戒免職
Yes.
對
And right before he was arrested…
然後在他即將被逮捕前…
My father…
父親他…
was proud of his job as a prosecutor.
對於檢察官的工作充滿了榮譽感
It's just impossible
那樣的他
that he would ever try fabricating evidence to achieve results.
竟然會為了立功而不惜捏造案件
I don't believe that, and I don't want to believe that.
我無法相信，也不願相信
If by any chance
就算萬一
my father actually did what he was suspected of doing,
家父做了任何有嫌疑的事
there must have been… a reason why.
也應該有什麼不得已的原因才對
That's what I…
我無論如何都想知道…
wanted to know.
此事的真相
If so then why do you think
既然如此我想問
your father didn't fight
你覺得令尊為何不選擇證明自身清白
to clear his name?
正面迎戰？
You must be concerned
你啊
because of what Masaki said.
很在意真樹說的話吧？
You killed Eisuke Tsuji, didn't you?
是你殺害了辻英介吧？
But what I presented in the trial with your father was all truthful.
但我在與令尊打官司時 陳述的都是事實
As recognized by the court.
判決結果也是如此認定的
I was committed to justice as an attorney.
我貫徹了身為律師的正義
And your father
而你的父親
lost.
則是輸了
It was a grievous incident.
那確實是令人心痛的事件
But your father
然而你的父親
administered justice to himself.
最終親手制裁了自己
Wasn't that what happened?
難道不是這樣嗎？
At least that's what I--
至少當時的我…
Even if so…
就算如此…
Even if that's the case,
就算事實真是如此
what does that have to do with Ms. Kaori Oikawa's death?
和及川香織小姐的意外有何關聯？
I'm sure he said…
真樹他說…
I-I'm sure of what Masaki said that day.
真樹先生他當時確實說了…
That's why that accident…
所以說才會發生那起事故…
Kaori was…
我將香織…
I have no knowledge beyond your father's case.
剩下的我就不清楚了
There's no way I can answer.
所以無法回答你
Are you asking me
你是以檢察官的身分
as a prosecutor?
在問我話嗎？
Or as the daughter of Eisuke Tsuji?
或者是作為 辻英介女兒的身分在問我？
I'm asking as both.
兩者皆是
Then I have to say it was a bit lousy
那麼以檢察官而言
as a prosecutor.
你的表現似乎有些糟糕呢
YOKOHAMA MUNICIPAL MINATO GENERAL HOSPITAL
（橫濱市立港綜合醫院）
Come in.
請進
The doctor will see you.
請進吧
Hello.
-麻煩你了 -請坐
Are you Mr. Masaki Nogi
你是野木真樹先生吧？
brought here in an ambulance?
前幾天被送來急救，沒錯吧？
Yes.
是的
Thank you for coming in.
不好意思把你找來
It's okay.
沒關係
There's something I wanted to tell you.
我有事想跟你說
When you can't get a statement, you obtain objective facts and evidence.
在無法取得供述時 就只能收集更多客觀事實與證據
Isn't that the basic method?
那是基本原則吧？
Uh…
什麼？
Especially if your opponent is formidable.
面對棘手的對象更是如此
Matsumoto Higashi Police Department?
請問是松本東警察署嗎？
I'm Nishimura from the Yokohama District Public Prosecutor's Office.
我是橫濱地檢中央分部的西村
I appreciate your kind assistance.
感謝平時的關照
I want to make an inquiry about an accident from 12 years ago.
關於在12年前的2012年7月
It occurred within the jurisdiction of Matsumoto Higashi in July 2012.
在松本東轄區內發生的汽車事故 我想問一些事
I was committed to justice as an attorney.
我貫徹了身為律師的正義
And your father
而你的父親
lost.
則是輸了
Or as the daughter of Eisuke Tsuji?
或者是作為 辻英介女兒的身分在問我？
How about the 17th? Next Saturday.
你覺得17號怎麼樣？就挑下週六
Huh? Sorry, what?
嗯？抱歉，你剛才說什麼？
Oh, I…
那個，我是說…
The day we're going to Nagano.
去長野的日子
How's next Saturday?
下週六如何？
Mm-hmm.
好
We've got to inform your mother about us getting married.
也得跟媽報告結婚的事
Yeah.
也對
Another difficult case?
又遇上難搞的案件了嗎？
Hmm?
嗯？
Lines on my brow?
我皺眉了嗎？
No.
真討厭
There are no lines. You're fine.
別擔心，沒有啦
But…
真是的
I don't want wrinkles.
我不想長皺紋啊
"It might be Masaki."
“說不定是真樹打來的”
That was my gut feeling.
我有那種預感
Not answering?
不用接嗎？
It's a number I don't know.
是沒見過的號碼
TOMO
（小知）
Hello? What's up, Tomo?
喂？小知，怎麼了？
Sorry to call so late. Can we talk?
抱歉這麼晚打來，你有空嗎？
It's all right with me.
是有空啦
Hold on a second.
等我一下
Hello? What is it?
喂？怎麼了？
You haven't met… Masaki again, have you?
那之後你應該沒跟真樹見面吧？
No, I haven't met him but…
見面倒是沒有…
But what?
發生了什麼事？
It's hard to explain on the phone. I-I'll tell you when I see you.
用電話講不太方便 我下次再慢慢解釋
What's hard to explain on the phone?
有什麼事是不能用電話講的？
Why are you so curious about Masaki?
你這麼在意真樹的事啊？
Well, you can't help it I guess.
不過也難怪啦
H-Hello?
喂？
Okay. I understand.
好吧，我明白了
Call me when you have some time.
等你有空再聯絡我
-Yeah. -Let's get together and talk.
-好 -我們當面聊吧
Okay, great. Thank you.
那樣也好，謝謝
Good night then.
那晚安囉
Yeah, good night.
好，晚安
Ah-ha! I startled you!
啊哈！嚇到你了…
Stop this "I startled you" nonsense! Hey, Nozomi!
“嚇到你了”？ 少給我搗蛋了，希實！
Nozomi!
希實！
Mom, we're here.
媽，我們回來了
Welcome home.
回來啦
-Oh, Ms. Nishimura. -Ah, Takashi.
-哦，媽 -啊，貴志先生
So nice of you to come at a busy time.
謝謝你在百忙之中還抽空來
-No problem. It's been a while. -Yes, it has been.
-別介意，久疏問候 -是啊，好久不見
I brought you this.
不嫌棄的話請收下吧
Thank you! Please have a seat.
謝謝你喔！來，快坐下吧
-Go ahead. -Thank you.
-坐吧 -好的
Hey, you'll have beer, won't you?
你們兩個，要喝啤酒對吧？
-Yes. -It should be fine.
-要 -沒問題吧
You didn't drive here.
畢竟你們不是開車來的嘛
I could see clearly how excited my mother was.
母親的雀躍全寫在臉上
She thought we were there to tell her we were planning to get married.
她覺得我們是來報告婚事
Of course that was true,
那麼想當然沒錯
but I realized my heart was heavy for some reason.
但我卻發覺自己並不感到興奮
Was it because of my father? Or Masaki?
是因為父親的事？
The restlessness in my life these days.
最近身邊實在太不安穩了
But that wasn't all.
不過不只是那樣
Hey. Are we really going to tell her about us getting married today?
我問你喔，今天真的要講這件事嗎？
We're not? Why?
不講嗎？為什麼？
Because I haven't given you an answer yet.
因為我根本還沒回覆你呀
I thought so. You didn't notice it.
我就知道，你根本沒注意到吧
Sorry to have kept you waiting.
抱歉讓你們久等了
Oops. I forgot the chopsticks.
糟了，忘了拿筷子了
Kanade, take care of this. As you can see, I'm on a roll these days.
-小奏，幫我放一下 -好
-On a roll? -On a roll…
-順利？ -順利…
I'm on a roll towards aging. It's embarrassing, honestly.
順利地持續老化，真是討厭啊
When did my mother become so cheerful?
母親是從何時起變得如此開朗的？
How did she overcome my father's death?
她是怎麼從父親的死走出來的呢？
-I'm so glad you could come. -Thank you.
-衷心歡迎你來 -謝謝
There you go.
來，請用
-I'll do it. -Thank you.
-我幫你倒 -謝謝
-Here.
-來 -謝囉
I'll fill it up for you.
泡沫偏多喔
Sorry.
抱歉喔
-I'll do it for you. -No, it's okay.
-換我幫你 -不，我自己倒就好了
-Okay. -Now, let's eat.
-好 -那我們就開動吧
Uh, before we start…
-好嗎？ -不好意思，在這之前…
Yes.
怎麼了？
-Um, well… -Huh?
-嗯？ -呃…
Kanade.
奏小姐
Will you marry me?
請跟我結婚
What?
什麼？
You said you hadn't answered yet, so…
因為你說你還沒回覆我
You didn't?
真的嗎？
Please give me your answer.
請給我一個答覆吧
Yes. I'd be happy to marry you.
我願意，今後也要請你多多指教了
My goodness…
太好了
I'm so glad…
謝天謝地
You two…
你們倆真是的
Hey, let's have a toast!
對了，我們來乾杯吧！
Yes. Cheers.
來，乾杯
Let's have a toast!
乾杯吧！
-Cheers. -Congratulations!
-乾杯 -恭喜喔！
Takashi. Take care of my daughter.
貴志先生，我家女兒就請你多關照了
-Of course. Please treat me favorably. -Of course.
-我才是呢，請多關照 -請多關照
Congratulations!
恭喜！
I've been drinking alone recently.
我最近迷上在晚上小酌幾杯
What?
真的假的？
Don't mind me if I pass out today. You can go home whenever you want.
要是我待會醉倒了 你們可以丟下我回去沒關係
I cannot do that.
那可不行
I'm a doctor.
我可是醫生啊
What is it? Did I say something weird?
怎麼了？我說了什麼奇怪的話嗎？
You've definitely found a good man, Kanade.
小奏，你遇上了好男人呢
Did you hear that?
我媽這麼說呢
I'm relieved.
太好了
I apologize for having to meet in this way, Mr. Nogi.
不好意思啊，律師 跟你約在這種地方見面
It's all right.
沒關係
Something worrisome came up.
我有點在意某件事
What do you mean?
什麼事？
Did you happen to meet
你最近見過她了嗎？
the daughter of Eisuke Tsuji recently?
就是辻英介的女兒
I'm impressed that you know.
你還真清楚啊
Kanade. What are you doing?
小奏，你在做什麼？
Looking for notebooks from my university days.
我在找大學時期的筆記本
Oh.
是喔
Takashi fell asleep. What should we do?
貴志先生睡著了耶，怎麼辦？
I wonder if I made him drink too much.
我是不是灌了他太多酒？
Just leave him alone.
讓他睡吧
Recently, he's had to perform a lot of operations so he must be tired.
他最近一直在開刀，可能也累了
-Are you busy these days too, Kanade? -Yeah.
-你工作也很忙嗎？ -是啊
But it's always that way.
不過這已經是常態了
You don't have to try so hard anymore.
你不用再勉強自己了
Huh?
什麼？
You've found your own happiness now.
你已經獲得屬於你的幸福了
I'm not trying too hard.
我沒勉強自己啊
Kanade, if you're still thinking about your father--
如果你還對爸爸的事耿耿於懷…
No, it's not like that. It's okay.
我沒有，不用擔心
I hope so.
那就好
You need to forget
關於爸爸的事
about your father.
你就忘掉吧
There are things better left unknown.
有些事不知道反而更好
Sometimes the past needs to be sealed.
有些過去還是封印起來比較好
You becoming a prosecutor was a surprise.
不過沒想到你居然當上了檢察官
I'm sure your father never dreamt of it.
你爸爸肯定做夢都沒想過吧
THE UNKNOWN SIDE OF FORMER PROSECUTOR AND ATTORNEY KOICHIRO NOGI
（前檢察官，野木浩一郎律師 不為人知的真實面貌）
Mr. Nogi is a former prosecutor.
野木律師當過檢察官
In 1988,
1988年
he was posted to Kagoshima District.
他任職於鹿兒島地檢
KAGOSHIMA DISTRICT BRANCH CHIEF HARA FAREWELL PARTY
（鹿兒島地檢，前分部長歡送會）
He was my father's colleague?
他是父親的前同事？
I was committed to justice as an attorney.
我貫徹了身為律師的正義
But why didn't he mention that fact to me
不過那時他為何
when we talked the other day?
絕口不提這件事呢？
Can I turn off the light?
我可以關燈嗎？
Hmm? Yes.
嗯？可以
What's the matter?
怎麼了？
What?
什麼？
You seem kind of down since this afternoon.
只是覺得你好像從白天就沒什麼精神
I don't think so.
沒有啊
I'm not feeling down, but…
沒那回事，但是…
Are you hesitant to get married?
你不想結婚嗎？
Huh?
你說什麼？
Of course not. What are you saying?
才沒有，你在胡說什麼啊？
Well,
沒有啦
we don't have to fixate on the idea of marriage.
如果你不想的話，也不一定要結婚
If you don't want to get married, we could just stay as is.
如果你不想結婚，保持現狀也可以
Huh?
什麼？
I never said I didn't want to get married.
我沒那麼想，別說傻話了
Then why did you say we should?
不然你又為何要跟我求婚？
You suddenly proposed to me.
還突然說要結婚
I wonder why myself.
我也想知道是為什麼
You should go check out the fridge.
我放在冰箱裡
What's in there?
放什麼？
Something I bought you.
我買了一樣東西要給你
This ring was in the fridge?
居然把戒指放在冰箱裡？
Why?
為什麼？
He's more mischievous than he seems.
原來他有淘氣的一面啊
Yeah. He doesn't seem the type, does he?
對啊，別看他一臉穩重的樣子
Congratulations!
恭喜你！
Thank you.
謝謝
-Huh? -What?
-你怎麼了啊？ -幹嘛？
I thought you'd be more excited.
還以為你會更開心
I'm not that young anymore, and we've lived together for almost two years.
我已經過那種年紀了啦 都同居兩年以上了
That's how it is?
是這樣嗎？
Yes, that's how it is.
就是這樣
It's not because of Masaki, is it?
該不會是為了真樹吧？
What?
什麼？
The reason you're not excited.
你不感到開心的原因
No, that's not it.
才不是呢
Well…
那個…
-To tell you the truth… -Yeah.
-其實啊… -嗯
I happened to see Masaki argue with his father.
我剛好撞見真樹和他父親爭吵的場面
Where?
在哪裡？
The Yokohama District Court lobby.
在橫濱地檢的大廳
I heard Masaki say
然後啊
that his father was the one
真樹說殺害我爸的
who killed my father.
就是他父親
And that Kaori's accident was connected to it.
還說香織的意外跟此事也有關聯
Masaki said that?
是真樹說的嗎？
Later on, we met and talked.
之後我和他見面，談了這件事
-With Masaki? -Um, no.
-你和真樹見面？ -那個，不是
With Masaki's father.
是真樹的父親
No way.
不會吧
What did he say?
他說什麼？
He said he only faced my father as an attorney against a prosecutor.
關於我父親的事
He didn't know about the accident.
對於那場車禍則是一無所知
But if you think about it,
不過你想想
on that day
在那個時候
Masaki's father came to the police station.
真樹的父親確實有到警察局
Then the accident was treated as negligence by Kaori.
結果那場車禍 被視作是香織自己造成的意外
He might have pressured them?
意思是他對警方施壓？
So,
然後呢
I made a request
我調查了一下
to the Nagano police station.
拜託長野的警察署配合
What I found out was
結果發現方向盤上面
Masaki's fingerprints were on the steering wheel.
留有真樹的指紋
You mean it wasn't an accident?
你認為那不是單純的意外？
I've never told anyone this before.
這是我第一次告訴別人這件事
But on that night, Masaki said something to me.
當天晚上真樹對我說了一些話
-That night? -The night of Kaori's wake.
-當天晚上？ -就是香織的守靈夜那天
Maybe…
我在懷疑…
I'm sorry!
對不起！
I'm the one who…
是我把香織…
He said he killed Kaori.
真樹或許是想說人是他殺的
No. That can't be.
怎麼可能
I know. It's unthinkable to me too.
我也覺得不可能，不會有那種事
There's something I've learned as a prosecutor.
但我在做檢察官的時候經常會想
The difference between committing a crime and not committing a crime
一個人犯不犯罪
is a very fine line.
真的都只是在一念之間
When unexpected things happen,
人在什麼時候會發生什麼事
people behave unexpectedly.
會做出什麼樣的行為
You never know when a person
是否會跨越界線
might step over a line.
誰也不會知道
You just don't know.
人的行為是難以預料的
That's why…
所以說啊
of course I want to believe my father and Masaki, but…
無論是對我父親或是真樹 我都想好好信任
I believe them as a daughter
那是出於我身為女兒
and as a friend.
以及友人的立場
But now,
但是啊
it's impossible
我已經沒辦法
for me to blindly believe them
盲目地一味相信了
as a prosecutor.
因為我是檢察官
Feeling like this
我也曾經想過
sometimes makes me think I shouldn't have become a prosecutor.
早知如此就不當檢察官了
But I can't back down now.
然而我無法回頭
Because I want to know the truth.
因為我想知道真相
I'm sorry I had to tell you this.
抱歉，跟你講這種事
It's okay.
沒關係
But you're the only one I could share this with.
但是我也只能找你傾訴
So after all…
我在想…
I…
小知，我啊…
I think I should go see Masaki and ask him
我想當面問真樹
about the accident.
關於車禍的事
What happened between him and Kaori on that day…
還有那天他到底 跟香織之間發生了什麼事
and why he appeared in front of me--
又是為了什麼目的再次出現…
Don't do it.
算了吧
-Why? -Because what if…
-為什麼？ -因為如果…
What if he actually did kill Kaori?
香織真的是真樹殺的怎麼辦？
I'm home.
我回來了
Crap, he's home already.
討厭，他回來了
He said he'd be late.
明明說會晚點回來的
Who's here? Do you have company?
有人來了？家裡有客人嗎？
Why are you asking?
你幹嘛問？
Hello. Long time no see.
好久不見，打擾了
Kanade.
小奏
Why are you shocked?
你為何要僵在那邊？
Didn't you say you would be late?
不是說今天會晚點回來嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
Well, the truth is…
那個，其實…
Hey, come on in.
喂，你快點進來啊
Hi.
嗨
What's going on?
這是怎麼一回事？
Um, so…
這個嘛，那個…
I contacted Yuki.
是我聯絡祐希的
That's why…
所以才會…
That's why you came to Kaori's memorial?
所以在香織的十二週年忌日 你才會來悼念？
You heard from him?
你是問祐希才得知的？
What are you guys secretly doing?
你們兩個幹嘛這樣偷偷摸摸的？
-But I couldn't-- -Masaki, you too.
-因為要是跟你說… -真樹，你也很奇怪
You don't have to hide from us.
要來的話就光明正大地來啊
Well… You know.
不過，也不用那麼兇嘛
But now everyone's here, so it's all good.
難得老友重逢
Hey. We might as well make a toast.
來，一起舉杯慶祝吧
How about it?
好嗎？
We should raise a glass to Kaori.
敬香織一杯
Come on. I even bought some pizzas.
過來啊，我還買了披薩回來呢，看吧
Raise a glass? Are you kidding?
還說什麼敬香織一杯？真不敢相信
Some nerve showing up, Masaki.
你還敢來露臉啊，真樹
What? But Tomo.
你是怎麼了？小知
You just said he doesn't have to hide. That's saying the opposite.
你說的話前後矛盾耶 剛才還叫他光明正大地來找我們
I'm just saying I can't believe
私底下做些偷雞摸狗的事
how you can show your face after being so secretive.
現在又厚著臉皮跑來我們家 讓人難以置信
So tell me, why didn't you ever call me?
我問你，為何之前都不聯絡我們？
And why did you come over here so suddenly?
如今又為何突然跑來？
Tomo. That's enough.
小知，別說了啦
I just wanted…
我就只是…
to see everybody.
想見大家而已
Masaki says he was
聽說真樹啊
out of the country this whole time.
之前一直都待在國外
Right?
對吧？
What were you doing?
你跑去做什麼？
Digging wells.
我在挖水井
-Wells? -Yeah.
-水井？ -對
He was working with NGOs.
他一直跟著非政府組織四處跑
going to developing countries and conflict areas.
去一些開發中國家或是戰亂地區
What?
那算什麼啊？
As a way of atonement for Kaori?
你這是為了向香織贖罪嗎？
Tomo.
小知
Sorry.
抱歉
I should leave now.
我還是回去好了
Huh?
什麼？
I apologize, Yuki.
抱歉，祐希
Tomo too.
對不起，小知
Kanade too.
小奏，我也對不起你
-Bye. -Hey, hold on--
-再見 -喂，等等…
You'd better not get close to Kanade.
你別接近小奏
Kanade's getting married soon.
她快要結婚了
She already has a man.
現在有男朋友了
I see.
這樣啊
Congratulations.
恭喜你
Show me.
借我看
I got a call from a girl.
有女生找我
I'll be right back.
我馬上回來
I missed you.
我好想你
What the hell is this?
這算什麼啊？
"It's now or never."
“這是最後的機會了”
I heard a voice inside me say.
在我心裡浮現了這樣的聲音
Kanade, don't go!
小奏，別追上去！
Why were you so harsh on him?
為何非得那樣說話啊？
You didn't have to say--
不必說得如此過分吧…
Because it's all my fault!
因為都是我不好！
Everything was my fault.
全都是我的錯
Masaki! Wait!
真樹！等一下！
I want to ask you something.
我有事想問你
What?
什麼事？
Why did you say what you said?
當時為何要說那種話？
What was the relationship between my father
我爸跟你父親
and your father?
究竟是什麼關係？
Did you know about the case my father was working on?
關於我爸的案件，你早就知情了？
And that your father
也知道你父親
was the attorney on the case?
就是我爸那個案件的律師？
And what does that
而那件事
have to do with
和香織的意外
Kaori's accident?
又有什麼關係？
What do you actually know, Masaki?
你其實知道些什麼？真樹
I want to know too.
我也想知道
Until I find out,
在找出真相之前…
in the meantime,
我暫時…
I'll be here.
留在這裡
What kind of guy is he?
對方是什麼樣的人？
Huh?
什麼？
Your husband-to-be.
你的結婚對象
What a lucky guy.
真羨慕他
He gets to marry you.
竟然能和你結婚
Don't be silly.
你在胡說什麼啊？
You're right.
也是
If I find out something,
如果我查出什麼
can I contact you?
能跟你聯絡嗎？
Was that call you?
用那組號碼？
Yeah.
對
That was me.
那是我打的
Y-You can.
好
Bye then.
再見
Kanade!
小奏！
Don't let go!
千萬不能放開喔！
Huh?
什麼？
Do you know there's a way to hold hands that can never be separated?
你知道絕對不會鬆手的握法嗎？
I know.
我知道
I know!
我知道啦！
It was his usual smile.
那是真樹平時的笑容
I knew I must not go.
雖然我知道自己不該去…
I knew I shouldn't, but…
我明明知道這點
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Sachs
字幕翻譯：葛亭筠
Why were Masaki's fingerprints there?
為什麼上面會有真樹的指紋？
Kaori!
香織！
If I'd killed her…
等同是我殺了她…
That's not fair, Tomo!
你太過分了，小知
It was me who…
是我將香織…
It's impossible.
我做不到